REGINA GALIEVA

rg-galieva.com github.com/rg-galieva linkedin.com/in/rg-galieva

Experienced full stack engineer, 9+ years in tech. Worked with projects of varying complexity both as an engineer and a team lead. Right now focused on front-end development. Passionate about sophisticated single page apps. In love with Javascript. Have strong skill in responsive layouts. The more challenging features - the better!

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-end: React, MobX, Redux, Typescript, Antd UI **Back-end:** Node, Express, Swagger, Postgres, Mongo

Styles: Sass, Less, PostCss, Css-modules, BEM

Tests: Unit test with Mocha, Jest

Version Control: Git, Svn

Dev Tools: Webpack, Grunt, Gulp, Babel, ESLint **Dev Deploy:** Heroku, Amazon S3, Jenkins **Familiar with:** JAVA EE (Spring, Tapestry),

Ruby (RoR), PHP (Wordpress)

Dev Methodology: Agile (Scrum + Kanban)

EXPERIENCE

[FR8STAR] - Senior Front End Engineer

Load board, freight matching, and bidding marketplace

SF Bay Area, CA May 2017- present

- Feature owner (front end): request-for-quote flow (entry point for shippers), rate calculator for shippers, load matcher (entry point for carriers), shipper registration, rate calculator widget for partners
- Worked on API-designs, global UI-acrhitecture, reusable responsive components library, style guides, performance optimization, 3rd-party API integration
- Tech stack: React, MobX, google maps API, Node, Swagger

[ADLUXE] - UI Team Lead

Moscow, RU 2015-2017

Creative technologies, Rich Media and Video Advertising Production

d the advised a great aft 10 to a financial ground durate

- Led the development of 10+ of company products
- Successfully implemented Agile methodology in a distributed, multi-timezone team
- Moved company website from PHP to React single page app
- Guided team in the development of SPA
- Created an educational tech program for managers and designers (dev fundamentals, is, git, webpack, jenkins)

[MAIL.RU GROUP] - Front End Developer

Moscow, RU

The leading Russian Internet company with 100M+ users

2013-2015

- Led UI development (code style, code structure, style guides)
- Cross platform development for desktop, mobile, in-game (awesomium) from scratch
- Made 3 global redesigns of the product. Implemented company style guide
- Led UI/UX testina
- Tech stack: Tapestry framework (Java), React, ¡Query.

[IFREE] - Web Developer

Saint-Petersburg, RU

Mobile App development & distribution company with \$250M year revenue

- Launched 20+ sites, landings, email newsletters, promo pages (PHP)
 RoR: Developed admin web applications for managing advertisement campaigns using Ruby on Rails
- Java EE: Web applications (front end, back end) using Spring MVC (Maven, JPA, JSP).

[SIMAI] - Web Developer

Ufa. RU

Digital studio «Simai» lead in the market of information solutions in Ufa

2008-2011

2011-2013

- HTML/CSS/JS coding of web pages, performance optimization, CMS layout templates

EDUCATION

UFA STATE AVIATION TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY

2005-2010

Master's degree in telecommunication systems

Saint-Petersburg, RU

- Was among TOP 20% of chosen to participate in the Academy

2013

Ufa, RU

- Took the 1st place among 10 projects.

GRAPHIC DESIGN BOOTCAMP

I-FREE TECHNICAL ACADEMY

Moscow, RU

10 weeks course: graphic design in web. Effective designs principles, theory and practice

2015